<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Thomas Pasquier</title>
    <link>https://tfjmp.org/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tfjmp.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://tfjmp.org/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://tfjmp.org/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>[538P] Topic in Computer Systems: Systems Security (2022-2023)</title>
      <link>https://tfjmp.org/post/2022-538p/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfjmp.org/post/2022-538p/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UNDER CONSTRUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this course is to expose students to a variety of topics in Systems Security.
Security inherently touches on all areas of computer science.
Therefore, this course was designed as a &lt;em&gt;breadth&lt;/em&gt; course, addressed to all students in the department.
The core idea underlying the course is to bring together a diversity of viewpoints to generate interesting discussions.
On the other hand, we could also easily design a &lt;em&gt;depth&lt;/em&gt; course focused on any of the topics we will discuss.
The project component is the opportunity for students to explore one of those topics in more depth.
Students are free (and encouraged) to apply their expertise (ML, PL, HCI, architecture etc.) to solve a specific Security problem.
Some of the papers have been selected explicitly to highlight the interdisciplinary nature of Systems Security and to showcase
how diverse perspectives are welcomed and appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-requirements&#34;&gt;Course Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no specific pre-requisite for this course outside of an undergraduate degree in Computer Science or closely related topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reason about security problems;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn to read, critique, and write security papers;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better understand the review process;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implement and evaluate a security prototype.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;class-format&#34;&gt;Class format&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a seminar-type class.
Every class we will discuss a different paper.
I have selected a mix of recent and older papers.
There will be two presenters during each class.
Each presenter will play a different role: the role of the Advocate and the role of the Critic.
The Advocate should play a role similar to that of the original authors and try to sell the work to the audience.
On the other hand, the Critic while remaining objective should towards the end of the presentation highlight the flaw of the paper and convince the audience that the paper is not good.
The Advocate presentation will last 20-25 minutes, you should motivate the work,
summarize the paper, and present the results.
The Critic presentation will last 10 minutes, you do not need to cover motivation
or summarization, instead you should focus on the shortcomings of the paper.
While shorter, the critical presentation is probably harder to prepare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to do well during your presentation, you should remember to stick to your role (Advocate or Critic).
Further, you do not need to spend too much time explaining the basics of the paper, everyone in the class will have already read it.
What add value to the presentation is your opinion and the insights you can extract from the paper! This is what you should focus on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should expect to present at least 2 or 3 times during the term depending on the number of students registered.
After the presentation, we will take a 10 minutes break and discuss the paper.
You should come prepared for those discussions and be ready to engage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;paper-reports&#34;&gt;Paper reports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each assigned paper you must write a report. You are to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/conferences/author-resources/paper-templates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;USENIX latex template&lt;/a&gt;
for formatting.
In your report, please, follow this structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&#34;paper-summary-no-more-than-250-words&#34;&gt;Paper Summary (no more than 250 words)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide a brief summary of the paper (3-5 sentences is usually enough). The aim is to demonstrate
that you’ve read (and understood) the paper, so try to paraphrase and extract the essentials. At this
stage you should aim to be objective; later sections allow for your own opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;answer-the-following-no-more-than-750-words-in-total&#34;&gt;Answer the following (no more than 750 words in total)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the problem? Why is it important? What is previous work insufficient (or Why has the
problem not been solved before, e.g. it’s a new problem the authors have identified). This is your take
on what the authors say in the paper (so again should be fairly objective). If the paper doesn’t seem
to tackle a particular problem, then focus on the primary motivation for the work. 1-2 sentences for
each of the three questions is probably sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-solution-or-approach&#34;&gt;The Solution (or Approach)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is their approach/solution? How does it solve the problem? How is the solution unique and/or
innovative (if it is)? What are the details? Once more you should use the paper itself as the source to
help you answer these questions– but, as in previous parts, please do not just copy sections from the
paper. Instead, you should focus on paraphrasing/synopsizing, and extracting the essential details.
Depending on the paper, you’ll probably need 5-10 sentences here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;evaluation&#34;&gt;Evaluation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do they evaluate their solution? What questions do they set out to answer? What does the
evaluation say about the strengths and weaknesses of their system? What are the strengths and weaknesses of the evaluation itself do you think? A total of 3-4 sentences should suffice here – we’re
looking for highlights, not a point-by-point reproduction of the evaluation section(s).
In the rare case that there is no evaluation section, skip this part of the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;questions-for-the-authors&#34;&gt;Questions for the Authors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re attending a talk about this paper given by one of the authors. List at least 2 questions
that you would like to ask. These should ideally be specific to the paper/research.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should submit 23 paper reports (subject to change). Each report done properly is equivalent to
1% of your final grade for a total of 20%. In practice, this means you have a few
&amp;ldquo;jokers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project&#34;&gt;Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project must address a non-trivial problem relevant to systems security. The project can resolve the problem by building a system, collecting data/carrying out experiments, developing algorithms and proving them correct, etc. I strongly prefer that you do your project in a team of 2-4 people.
You are encouraged to apply techniques from your main area of expertise to the topic of security (e.g., perform intrusion detection using ML techniques).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should plan to schedule some time to chat about your project idea with me.
Please, do not hesitate to send me an e-mail as soon as you want to discuss it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The required project deliverables are listed below.
Written submissions will be made through TBC and must be formatted using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/conferences/author-resources/paper-templates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;USENIX latex template&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Proposal Draft:&lt;/strong&gt; You are to submit the draft of your proposal on [hotcrp]. It will not be directly graded but will receive reviews from your peers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proposal Presentation:&lt;/strong&gt; You will prepare a short presentation describing the project you intend to work on. Each presentation will be followed by a Q&amp;amp;A session. Presentation timing and details TBD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proposal Peer Review:&lt;/strong&gt; each student will review proposals from other groups and give feedback. You should take this task seriously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Proposal:&lt;/strong&gt; you should incorporate feedback from the peer review process. I also strongly encourage you to schedule time to chat with me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Report Draft:&lt;/strong&gt; You are to submit the draft of your report on [hotcrp]. It will not be directly graded but will receive reviews from your peers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Presentation:&lt;/strong&gt; You will prepare a presentation describing your project. I encourage you to demo your project during your talk. Each presentation will be followed by a Q&amp;amp;A session. Presentation timing and details TBD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report Peer Review:&lt;/strong&gt; as per the proposal stage, you will be asked to review the report from other teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Report:&lt;/strong&gt; you should incorporate feedback from the peer review process. I also strongly encourage you to schedule time to chat with me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&#34;proposal-instuction&#34;&gt;Proposal Instuction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your proposal should be short (~4 pages). The main objective is to
assess the viability of the proposed project. You are expected to have
completed a limited amount of work at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It must contain the following element:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem statement&lt;/strong&gt; (4 paragraphs): &lt;em&gt;Paragraph 1)&lt;/em&gt;  At a high level, what is the
problem area you are working on, and why is it important? It is important
to set the larger context here. Why is the problem of interest and
importance to the larger community? &lt;em&gt;Paragraph 2)&lt;/em&gt; What is the specific problem
considered in this paper? This paragraph narrows down the topic area of the
paper. In the first paragraph, you have established general context and
importance. Here you describe a specific context and background.
&lt;em&gt;Paragraph 3)&lt;/em&gt; What general approach are you planning to take?
Why do you expect significant results? You won&amp;rsquo;t have done the work at this
stage, but you should think about the results you expect to obtain.
&lt;em&gt;Paragraph 4)&lt;/em&gt; At a high level, what are the differences between what you are doing
and what others have done?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Work&lt;/strong&gt; (1 page): There are two types of related work: background work
and contextual work. Background work includes contributions that are required to
understand your work. They must be described in sufficient detail so that any
of your classmates can understand what you are doing and why. Contextual work
is necessary to help the readers place your work and identify your
contributions. This includes past contributions you build upon in your own solution,
work that solves the same problem but in different ways, and contributions from
adjacent areas (solving a similar problem in a different domain). It is important
to remember that doing something differently is not a contribution. It must be
clear why you are taking an alternative approach (e.g., you exercise different trades-off,
improve performance, etc.). You may have yet to perform
an exhaustive literature review when submitting the proposal. Still, you need to have identified important work,
know where to look for more, and clearly understand how your proposal differs
from previous work. If you identify flaws in past work that you aim to address,
identify and state them clearly. If you have yet to read all the papers you intend
to read; you should list all those you have identified and plan to read. You
should also identify areas/domains where you plan to look for relevant
work. However, you should explicitly compare your proposed solution to some
previous work (a few sentences per publication are enough).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experimental setup&lt;/strong&gt; (1 page): What experiments will you conduct? Why? What
question is each experiment designed to answer? What do you hope to learn from
each experiment? What measurement tools will you use? How will you determine if
your measurements are accurate? What tests will you conduct conditionally?
(For example, if we learn X from experiment 1, then we must
do A else do B.) What problems do you expect?
This part is essential to receive meaningful feedback and plan your
research. This is where most of the proposal effort should go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources Needed&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;lt;1 page): What equipment/software/tool will you need?
Do you have access to it? How could you get access? You do not want to find out,
midway through the project, you need access to resources that are not available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schedule&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;lt;1 page): You should be as precise as you can, identify important
milestones, and make sure you allocate time to write the report and incorporate
peers feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;report-instruction&#34;&gt;Report Instruction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should write your final report as you would write a research paper. Your
report should be at most 13 pages, including figures and tables, but excluding
references. Be sure to highlight your work&amp;rsquo;s limitations honestly
and discuss when your results did not meet your expectations/hypothesis. Try to explain why this happens. I expect some of the reports you submit to
be suitable to be turned into conference submissions. I am more than happy to
work with you to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;deadlines-tbc&#34;&gt;Deadlines (TBC)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Proposal Draft:&lt;/strong&gt; Friday, February 9th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proposal Presentation:&lt;/strong&gt; Wednesday, February 15th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proposal Peer Review:&lt;/strong&gt; Friday, February 17th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Proposal:&lt;/strong&gt; Monday, February 27th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Report Draft:&lt;/strong&gt; Friday, April 7th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Presentation:&lt;/strong&gt; Wednesday, April 12th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report Peer Review:&lt;/strong&gt; Friday, April 14th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Report:&lt;/strong&gt; Friday, April 28th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peer Review 10%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project (group) 55%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper reports 20%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation(s) 10%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participation (in-class discussion) 5%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;schedule--reading-list-subject-to-change&#34;&gt;Schedule &amp;amp; Reading List (subject to change)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Day&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Paper&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Presenters&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 9 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Introduction - Course Overview - Reading a Paper &lt;br/&gt; Reading (no report): &lt;a href=&#34;https://cseweb.ucsd.edu/~dstefan/cse227-spring19/papers/keshav:how.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How to read a paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 11 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8523802&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A Study on the Security Implications of Information Leakages in Container Clouds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 16 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gzs715.github.io/pubs/HOUDINI_CCS19.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Houdini&amp;rsquo;s Escape: Breaking the Resource Rein of Linux Control Groups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 18 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/conference/osdi16/osdi16-arnautov.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SCONE: Secure Linux Containers with Intel SGX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 23 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.dse.in.tum.de/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/rkt-io-eurosys21.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rkt-io: a direct I/O stack for shielded execution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 25 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/conference/usenixsecurity18/sec18-sun.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Security Namespace: Making Linux Security Frameworks Available to Containers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 30 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www-users.cse.umn.edu/~kjlu/papers/kara.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demons in the Shared Kernel: Abstract Resource Attacks Against OS-level Virtualization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 1 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/1199328&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Anomaly detection using call stack information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 6 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/924295&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A fast automaton-based method for detecting anomalous program behaviors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 8 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/pdf/10.1145/2939672.2939783&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fast Memory-efficient Anomaly Detection in Streaming Heterogeneous Graphs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 13 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/pdf/10.1145/3460120.3484589&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepAID: Interpreting and Improving Deep Learning-based Anomaly Detection in Security Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 15 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Proposal Presentation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 20 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Midterm Break&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 22 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Midterm Break&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 27 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://users.cs.northwestern.edu/~robby/courses/395-495-2017-winter/ndss2008.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Automated whitebox fuzz testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 1 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/woot20-paper-fioraldi.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AFL++: Combining Incremental Steps of Fuzzing Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 6 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/conference/usenixsecurity17/sec17-schumilo.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;kAFL: Hardware-assisted feedback fuzzing for OS kernels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 8 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.cse.ohio-state.edu/~zhao.2708/assets/ndss18/NDSS18.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IoTFuzzer: Discovering Memory Corruptions in IoT Through App-based Fuzzing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 13 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/conference/usenixsecurity18/sec18-he.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Rethinking Access Control and Authentication for the Home Internet of Things (IoT)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 15 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/pdf/10.1145/3355369.3355577&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Information Exposure From Consumer IoT Devices: A Multidimensional, Network-Informed Measurement Approach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 20 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cs.uwaterloo.ca/~brecht/courses/854-Scalable-Systems-Software-2011/Possible-Readings/virtualization/secure-virtual-arch-sosp-2007-criswell.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Secure Virtual Architecture: A Safe Execution Environment for Commodity Operating Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 22 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pdos.csail.mit.edu/papers/lxfi:sosp11.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Software fault isolation with API integrity and multi-principal modules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 27 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.net/system/files/atc19-narayanan.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LXDs: Towards isolation of kernel subsystems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 29 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nebelwelt.net/publications/files/22NDSS2.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Preventing Kernel Hacks with HAKC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 3 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/osdi20-narayanan_vikram.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RedLeaf: Isolation and Communication in a Safe Operating System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 5 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/319151.319163&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EROS: a fast capability system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 10 Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/~dc552/papers/201505-oakland2015-cheri-compartmentalization.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cheri: A hybrid capability-system architecture for scalable software compartmentalization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 12 Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project Presentation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;late-policy&#34;&gt;Late Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will receive a 0 for late work unless you have an approved extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For individual assignments, the deadline for one assignment can be extended by 24 hours with no penalty to the mark. Extension requests must be made explicitly through e-mail. Extension requests must be made no later than 24 hours past the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For group tasks, you can request an extension of 24 hours as long as someone in your group has an unused extension. You cannot receive an extension of more than 24 hours for a group deliverable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;academic-honesty-and-collaboration-guidelines&#34;&gt;Academic honesty and collaboration guidelines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The department has a detailed policy regarding &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.cs.ubc.ca/docs/collaboration-plagiarism&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;collaboration and plagiarism&lt;/a&gt;. You must familiarize yourself with this policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper reports:&lt;/strong&gt; You should write your reports individually. You are free to discuss with others,
but you must write the reports on your own. You should clearly reference any resources you have used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Projects:&lt;/strong&gt; you are free to use any code you find in your project. However, a non-trivial fraction of functionality in your prototype must be constructed by your team. You must cite and attribute sources of the code that you borrow/utilize in your project. When writing the project reports, you should follow the same citation standard as expected from conference papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;extra-reading-material&#34;&gt;Extra Reading Material&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cseweb.ucsd.edu/~dstefan/cse227-spring19/papers/keshav:how.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How to read a paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/academic-program/write-great-research-paper/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How to write a great research paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/publication/how-to-give-a-good-research-talk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How to give a good research talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sigarch.org/reviewing-system-security-papers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reviewing System Security Papers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/teaching/1011/R01/review-writing.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Writing reviews for systems conferences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://andreas-zeller.info/2021/07/27/Reviewing-across-fields-ICSE-PLDI-CCS.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How do different fields review papers? Experiences from ICSE, PLDI, and CCS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Research Proficiency Evaluation process</title>
      <link>https://tfjmp.org/post/rpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfjmp.org/post/rpe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The official guidelines are provided on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.ubc.ca/students/grad/policies/grad-handbook/research-proficiency-evaluation-rpe/rpe-process&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;department website&lt;/a&gt;.
On this page, I give my take on the process and provide some pointers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-goal-of-the-rpe&#34;&gt;The goal of the RPE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the RPE is to 1) make sure you are ready for research; and
2) that the supervisory relationship is working. It is best to identify problems
early, and the goal is not to fail you but to ensure you are ready to succeed.
In my opinion, the RPE should be a well-defined, reasonably scoped, and
self-contained project. The RPE is not your Ph.D., you should think of it as
starting to work on your first paper (at UBC) and it should be scoped
consequently. You may have a grand ambition for your Ph.D.,
but you need to wrap the RPE project in only a few months.
Consequently, you need to identify a set of clear and meaningful objectives where
you can make significant progress within the available time frame.
There is an expectation that your RPE will lead to a publication, but this is
not expected to happen before your defense. However, you need to show you are
working in that direction (e.g., by showing preliminary results and a prototype).
Finally, The self-contained aspect is important if you are working as part
of a larger project, the RPE must be based on your work and your contribution
must be clearly identifiable.
My role is to work with you, support you, and make sure things go smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deliverable&#34;&gt;Deliverable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For written reports, I suggest using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/conferences/author-resources/paper-templates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;USENIX template&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RPE proposal&lt;/strong&gt;: expected length is around two pages. This should focus on the problem
definition. However, from experience, most students submit slightly longer proposals (5-6 pages)
including an expanded related work section and a description of their proposed solution.
This is not necessary, but you should feel free to include this if you want feedback on those aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RPE report&lt;/strong&gt;: expected length is around twelve pages. Your report should be
written and organized like a conference paper. You may consider including a long
discussion section containing: 1) limitations of your current prototype/proof of concept; 2) work
you are planning to do over the next few months to turn your RPE work into a publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RPE presentation&lt;/strong&gt;: expected length is around twenty minutes. You should present
your work as you would at a conference. You should cover the following topics: 1) context and problem;
2) solution; 3) evaluation; and 4) future work. You should
rehearse your presentation (you can ask me and your peers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should not hesitate to discuss with other students in the lab, and ask for examples
of their submissions. Further, I am expecting to see several drafts of your
written work/presentation. I will normally ask for it, but you should feel free
to send it to me as soon as you want feedback. Unlike work you do for a joint paper submission, I will avoid rewriting your text. However, I am more than happy to (and will) comment.
I also encourage you to share drafts with some of your peers working on
different projects (forming a writing group with other students taking their RPE at the same time can be a very positive experience). Sharing your work with peers help you gauge how accessible your writings are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deadlines&#34;&gt;Deadlines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assume a student starting in September (if you start in January, tweak the timeline accordingly).
Here is my vision of how you should approach the RPE process.
Remember, as your advisor/supervisor it is my job to get you through this process
successfully. This means you should talk to me and seek help and support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September&lt;/strong&gt;, you hopefully have an idea of why you came to UBC and what you want to work on.
You should spend your first few months getting familiar with the relevant literature,
writing an annotated bibliography/notes about your reading, and start designing and implementing prototypes to test your ideas.
In addition, you may also decide to join an existing project, get up to speed with the project, and participate actively.
During our 1-1 meeting I would expect to discuss your growing understanding of
the field, and your ideas. Part of my job is to challenge your ideas
and force you to think critically about the problems you propose to investigate and potential solutions.
Defining research problems is one of the most important skills to acquire early on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December&lt;/strong&gt;, you should start crystalizing the research problem you want to
tackle during your RPE. Identify, the relevant literature and what is the state
of the art in that space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January&lt;/strong&gt;, this is the time to start working on the proposal. In addition to formalizing and writing down your proposal, you should consider doing some preliminary technical experimentation. My advice is to take only a single course during this term. You want to ensure you have enough
time dedicated to research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;, we select together your RPE committee. This is relatively simple,
we need to identify two faculties such that their interests overlap with your RPE project
and who have time to seat on your committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt;, you submit your proposal and get feedback from the committee. You should
expect again your ideas to be challenged in a supportive way. The goal is to help
you formulate a clear problem. You should digest the feedback and make corrections
accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May&lt;/strong&gt;, you can now start working on your project in earnest. At this point,
you should be done with courses and you should be able to focus on your research
full-time. You are strongly encouraged to do so. I am expecting to get messages
from students several times a week at this point. Don&amp;rsquo;t be shy, if you need to
discuss your struggles and/or design decisions do so! You may also want to chat
with other students in the lab, especially those working on related topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August&lt;/strong&gt;, you have hopefully been taking notes on your implementation, design,
and the literature you have read. It is time to write your RPE report. Remember,
the goal is to show you are able to perform research at a level expected from a
Ph.D. student. You may not have finished everything you wanted to do, but you need
to show at least an early prototype and some early evaluation results. You should also
demonstrate that you understand how to move from what you have to a publication
(i.e., clearly articulate the work you are planning to do over the next few months).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September&lt;/strong&gt;, it is time to submit the report and organize the defense. Do not
be overly concerned with the defense. You will be told before the presentation is scheduled if there are
any concerns about the quality of the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;failing-the-rpe&#34;&gt;Failing the RPE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, a student failing during the public defense should be avoided and
in most circumstances would be the supervisor&amp;rsquo;s responsibility.
There are multiple deadlines within the RPE that are opportunities to give
feedback and to have a difficult conversation if things are not going as they
should.
Your proposal and report are read by your supervisor and the committee members, you
should be told if there are concerns about their standard.
If that is the case, you should work with your supervisor on a positive outcome.
This outcome will depend on why things are not working well and can include
solutions such as an extension, looking for a new supervisor, or continuing in
the MSc program if you are a Ph.D. track student.
I also strongly encourage you to talk with other faculties or your peers in such
circumstances and to seek support to decide on your next steps.
In short, the process is designed to avoid failure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with me</title>
      <link>https://tfjmp.org/post/working-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfjmp.org/post/working-with-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page describes my typical expectations when interacting with students as an adviser.
I aim to tailor my advising style to fit each student&amp;rsquo;s needs, but this is the general starting point of our relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-contact-me&#34;&gt;How to contact me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best time to discuss research is during our project or 1-on-1 meetings.
Outside of those, the best way to contact me is through instant messaging (using Systopia&amp;rsquo;s discord server is probably the best way to get hold of me).
Instant messaging is ideal for informal exchanges and discussing day-to-day research progress.
I am expecting that students would be in touch a few times during the week, and I may probe about your progress.
In case of more formal interactions, for example, to complete some administrative task, e-mails at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tfjmp@cs.ubc.ca&#34;&gt;tfjmp@cs.ubc.ca&lt;/a&gt; are the best choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interactions-outside-of-working-hours&#34;&gt;Interactions outside of working hours&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academics are notorious for working at asocial hours.
I may send a message at a random time during the week, for example, as I was reading a paper that I think is interesting and relevant to your research.
However, I do not expect an immediate response.
Similarly, you should not expect an immediate response to a message sent at 3 am.
However, I endeavor to respond within one working day whenever possible and would expect the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meetings&#34;&gt;Meetings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am expecting to meet my advisees regularly (at least once a week).
I track my meetings with google calendar.
If a meeting is not on my calendar I am unlikely to show up.
I expect students to come to the meeting or to let me know in advance if they cannot.
Students are responsible for running the meetings and should be proactive.
This means preparing a report on their progress and important points to discuss.
Students should send a written update the day before with clear indications of any document I should read before the meeting (e.g., important related work, paper/report draft, code etc.).
I get extremely frustrated if I am expected to have a meaningful interaction on a 15 pages paper I haven&amp;rsquo;t read.
Debugging code, system setups, and the like is best done asynchronously through instant messaging and should generally not be the topic of our meetings.
This means that if you get stuck on a technical issue, you should contact me ASAP so I can have a look and hopefully help.
Finally, I have to divide time between multiple students, projects, and other responsibilities.
This means that it is vital for your own progress that you take the lead in moving your project forwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cancel meeting when you have nothing to discuss.&lt;/strong&gt;
It is fine to drop me a message to tell me you haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to make meaningful progress and would like to cancel a meeting.
Obviously, I would not expect multiple meetings to be canceled in a row (unless you are facing hardship in such case do let me know so I can ensure you get support).
I would expect heads up on canceled meetings to come sufficiently early as to be respectful of the time of all people involved in those meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cancel meeting if something urgent happens.&lt;/strong&gt;
We all get sick and have family issues or personal matters to deal with.
This means that at some point meetings may need to be canceled and this is fine.
You should just make sure to let everyone involved know as soon as you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;managing-software-artifacts&#34;&gt;Managing Software Artifacts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most research at UBC is enabled through public funds.
This means that we have a duty to be transparent about the outcome of our work and to share it with the wider community.
In practice, this means that you should properly manage your software artifacts.
This includes practices such as documenting, using version control, using proper licenses etc.
The default assumption is that your code and any other artifacts will be made publicly available after the corresponding paper is published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also important to produce software that can run.
Consequently, I tend to insist on the use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_integration&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;continuous integration tools and practices&lt;/a&gt; and I would expect us to set this up together in the early stage of a project.
I am also a big fan of disposable and reproducible development environments and I strongly encourage you to look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;how to use Vagrant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interpersonal-communication-and-cultural-expectations&#34;&gt;Interpersonal Communication and Cultural Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UBC is an English-speaking and liberal environment with its own cultural expectations.
However, this may sometimes be at odds with what you have been experiencing while growing up.
Other mismatches of expectations may arise from class, religion, sexual orientation, and many other dimensions that compose your identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YMyofREc5Jk&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These differences in expectations and perceptions can create tensions.
This means that we all need to be mindful of each other.
Living in a multicultural society requires understanding and kindness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;paper-writing&#34;&gt;Paper Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should aim to submit the best paper we can.
This means that we may miss a deadline if I feel that the paper is not ready.
I &lt;strong&gt;do not&lt;/strong&gt; write papers at the last minute.
I expect a full draft of a submission with full evaluation to be ready one or two weeks before the deadline and the final week to be dedicated to polish and styling.
Consequently, I aim to specify the target conference long in advance and to revise our target if it becomes clear that we won&amp;rsquo;t have a quality submission ready by the deadline.
However, note that more and more top-tier conferences have multiple deadlines during the year.
This means, in practice, that we can submit a much stronger paper a few months later.
You are &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; to submit a paper without the explicit consent of all authors.
Authors are expected to be available around paper deadlines and you should be mindful of those when making other commitments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing a paper requires much more effort than most junior graduate students expect.
We will go through multiple iterations with the first draft being significantly different from the final submitted version.
You are expected to seek and take feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authors ordering is important and must be discussed between the authors.
The first author is generally the student who has done most of the work, followed by other students that assisted.
Follow faculty members with the senior authors generally being the advisor of the first author.
Please, discuss if/when you have a concern about the ordering of authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All papers must be written in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LaTeX&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt;.
You are expected to learn to use LaTeX and the associated toolset.
I will create a private GitHub repository with the template for the paper.
We will normally &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; use overleaf or similar tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you are the first author you have some additional responsibilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are in charge of driving the paper forwards and organizing meetings;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are expected to take a significant share of the writing;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must ensure that the paper follows submission guidelines (page limits, formatting, anonymity, etc.);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must submit the paper before the deadline and ensure that all authors are happy with the submission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect to be regularly involved in the writing process and I will provide regular feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vtIzMaLkCaM&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication-expectations&#34;&gt;Publication Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MSc students should aim to complete at least one major conference paper before they graduate.
PhD students should target at least three major conference papers before they graduate.
Those are not official guidelines, but serve as an indication of what a student doing &amp;ldquo;well&amp;rdquo; looks like.
Publications are in a sense more important than the degree you will obtain and must be one of the main focus of your time at UBC.
For example, obtaining a PhD will be the minimum requirement if you apply for an academic position, the work you have published will be the most important criteria when assessing your application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lab-life--service&#34;&gt;Lab Life &amp;amp; Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you join my team you will be part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.ubc.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Department of Computer Science at UBC&lt;/a&gt; and in particular of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://systopia.cs.ubc.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Systopia Lab&lt;/a&gt;.
As such, there are some expectations where participation in lab life is concerned.
You are expected to come to the lab regularly and interact with your colleagues (collaborations are very important and the interactions between graduate students are an integral part of a successful graduate experience).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are also expected to participate in the life of the lab, attend reading group sessions, and presentations.
There is also a number of positions to be filled every year, including organizing social events, maintaining our website, managing our social media presence, and more.
Those activities are led by students, and it is expected that, as you become familiar with the lab, you will start participating actively.
You may also wish to participate in department-level or university-level service.
Finally, you may want to get involved with the research community by participating in different activities such as artifacts evaluation committee, shadow program committee, and program committee.
This is also encouraged and I am happy to provide support if needed and as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should note that those activities are important and can help with your career progression.
Multiple fellowships explicitly mention those in selection criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nickcerconescholarship.ca/?page_id=14&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IEEE Canadian Foundation Nick Cercone Graduate Scholarship in Computer Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weight will also be attached to the student’s academic excellence and to her or his involvement in helping others (e.g. tutoring, service on a student council, organizing student activities, and volunteer work outside the university).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nserc-crsng.gc.ca/Students-Etudiants/PG-CS/CGSD-BESCD_eng.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Canada Graduate Scholarships – Doctoral program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professional, academic and extracurricular activities as well as collaborations with supervisors, colleagues, peers, students and members of the community, such as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;teaching, mentoring, supervising and/or coaching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;managing projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;participating in science and/or research promotion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;participating in community outreach, volunteer work and/or civic engagement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chairing committees and/or organizing conferences and meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;participating in departmental or institutional organizations, associations, societies and/or clubs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are obviously some circumstances that may prevent you from participating.
You may also need to be away from the lab for some time (e.g., family or health issues).
This is perfectly fine but this should be discussed in advance to ensure you have proper support (there is a number of initiative within the university to support students going through hardships).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;equipment&#34;&gt;Equipment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you require equipment to pursue research, I am happy to purchase it for you.
However, this equipment will be purchased through grant money.
This means that the equipment is the property of UBC and that you should take care of it and use it with this in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;raship-and-taship&#34;&gt;RAship and TAship&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you have secured a fellowship (you are strongly encouraged to look for those as it will strenghten your CV significantly), you are likely to be funded through RAship or TAship.
Most of you will be familiar with Teaching Assistant duties.
You will receive monetary compensation and it is therefore expected that you behave professionally and perform your duties to the best of your ability.
Fulfilling expectations of those roles take precedence over your coursework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New students joining the group will be expected to work as a teaching assistant during their first year unless agreed otherwise.
We will most likely discuss RAship opportunities towards the end of your first year.
Those opportunities are dependent on funding availability, and your academic and research progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Assistantships are generally funded through specific grants.
The funder allocates money for us to work on a specific research topic.
This means two things: 1) there is some expectation for us to produce results (this includes papers and software artifacts); and 2) that we work within the context of the funding agreement.
This means that by taking a RAship you must work on the agreed-upon topic.
It is my job to make sure the grant gives you a reasonable degree of freedom but if we agreed to do research on how to make the best pizza, we may not be able to work on how to make the best paella.
If you wish to change your research topic, you must discuss this in advance and as early as possible.
Similarly, if there is no sufficient progress as to fulfil our engagement with the funder, we may discuss alternative route to fund your research.
Note, that I may not be able to provide the same amount financial support outside of our original agreed uppon topic.
If you make extra-work commitments (side-projects, consulting, extra-teaching, etc.), I must be made aware.
Be aware that some grants/funding are tied to IP agreements and it may affect work you do on closely related topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;internships&#34;&gt;Internships&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internships are a great opportunity to gain new skills, build your network and expand your horizon.
I strongly encourage graduate students, especially, PhD students to seek such a position during the course of their degree.
You should try to identify an internship that &lt;em&gt;helps&lt;/em&gt; with your research and career goal (acquiring complementary skills, researching a related topic etc.).
It is possible to get an internship at any point during you degree, however, internships done a few years in your degree tend to be more valuable (you are productive much faster, you can more effectively leverage the network you will build etc.), further the first summer(s) are likely to be the time when you start your research in earnest.
You should start to think about internship towards the end of the &lt;em&gt;Winter 1 term&lt;/em&gt; of the year you are planning to do your summer internship.
Talk to faculties and students in Systopia, and more importantly talk with me!
You should also be mindful of any engagement you have (Are you part of a team that is working for a submission during the summer? Have you signed to TA some summer course? Are you expected to produce some report as part of your degree? Is it ok given your source of funding?).
Finally, remember that immigration issues may affect your eligibility for internships.
This is a complex matter and faculties are generally ill-equipped to help.
The best source of advice on the matter at UBC is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://students.ubc.ca/about-student-services/international-student-advising&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;International Student Advising&lt;/a&gt; service.
You should contact them as you start planning to apply for internships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;phd-timeline&#34;&gt;Ph.D. Timeline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the official timeline on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.ubc.ca/students/grad/policies/grad-handbook/phd-program/phd-program-timeline&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;department website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year 1 - Prepare and pass the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tfjmp.org/post/rpe/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Research Proficiency Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year 2/3 - PhD Proposal and course requirement completion, move to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.grad.ubc.ca/current-students/managing-your-program/advancement-candidacy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;candidacy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventually (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.grad.ubc.ca/prospective-students/graduate-degree-programs/phd-computer-science&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; 3.33 years &amp;amp; &amp;lt; 9 years ; on average 5.77 years&lt;/a&gt;) submit and defend your PhD thesis!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;self-evaluation-form&#34;&gt;Self-evaluation form&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of each term, students should fill a &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/bBwwzYCtjpoVVTha6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;self-evaluation form&lt;/a&gt;.
The goal is for you to reflect on your progress and to identify potential problems early.
I also want to ensure that you are well supported.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Admission Interview (Season 2022)</title>
      <link>https://tfjmp.org/post/2022-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfjmp.org/post/2022-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;candidate-presentation-15min&#34;&gt;Candidate presentation (15min)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start the interview with a brief presentation to give you an opportunity to give voice to your application material.
Use this presentation to explain who you are, what you have done, and what you want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce yourself (~1min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss a research project you worked on, clearly focusing on your contribution (~10min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss why you want to go to UBC/work with X supervisor/advisor (~4min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are aware that there are systemic barriers that prevent students from realizing their full potential.
For example, you may not have been able to engage in as many research projects you would have liked to for a number of different reasons such as the fact that your home institution is not a research intensive university, you needed to work to pay your tuition, you had family responsibilities etc.
We understand this, and we want to consider each student&amp;rsquo;s potential and help them realize that potential.
You should feel free to point this out during your presentation if you feel comfortable doing so and as you judge it to be appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;questions-to-the-applicant-10min&#34;&gt;Questions to the applicant (10min)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following your presentation, we will undoubtedly want to ask you questions about your work as well as questions to assess how well your research interests fit into our lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;paper-reading-10min&#34;&gt;Paper reading (10min)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please pick &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; paper from the following list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/pdf/10.1145/3448016.3457568&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Negi, Parimarjan, et al. &amp;ldquo;Steering Query Optimizers: A Practical Take on Big Data Workloads.&amp;rdquo; Proceedings of the 2021 International Conference on Management of Data (SIGMOD). 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ndss-symposium.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/24065-paper.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paccagnella, Riccardo, et al. &amp;ldquo;Custos: Practical tamper-evident auditing of operating systems using trusted execution.&amp;rdquo; Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS). 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/sec21-alsaheel.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Alsaheel, Abdulellah, et al. &amp;ldquo;ATLAS: A Sequence-based Learning Approach for Attack Investigation.&amp;rdquo; 30th Security Symposium (USENIX Security). 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/sec21-bahmani.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bahmani, Raad, et al. &amp;ldquo;CURE: A Security Architecture with CUstomizable and Resilient Enclaves.&amp;rdquo; 30th Security Symposium (USENIX Security). 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should pick a paper that appears to be the most relevant to the research you are thinking of pursuing.
Reading academic papers is difficult; learning to do so will be an important skill you will acquire in graduate school.
This part of the interview is intended to gauge your ability to engage with the literature and how you think about the research literature.
Do not be intimidated, you will be assessed based on reasonable expectations for someone at your stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may prepare some slides to discuss the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summarize key points/insights of the paper/what surprised you? [no need to explain the whole thing] (~5min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would you extend/build on the paper? (~5min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;discussion-about-research-10min&#34;&gt;Discussion about research (10min)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on your presentation, we will discuss research directions you could explore during your degree.
The goal is for all parties to gauge the fit between our interests and discuss the general area of research you will pursue during your time at UBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;questions-from-the-applicant-15min&#34;&gt;Questions from the applicant (15min)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the time for you to ask questions about the lab, UBC, Vancouver or anything you would like to know.
I am also more than happy to put you in touch with my students if you want to hear first hand about students&amp;rsquo; experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;after-the-interview&#34;&gt;After the interview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time between the interview and a decision may vary.
There are multiple factors at play: progress on interviewing other candidates on the shortlist, how busy the committee is, administrative aspects etc.
We try to give offers as early as possible, but the department continues to make offers all the way into April.
Consequently, do not worry if you don&amp;rsquo;t hear back immediately.
On the other hand, if you get another offer and you need to make a decision, do not hesitate to get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you get an offer, it is important for us to make sure you feel welcomed to the lab and prepare the support you will need.
It is the right time to bring up issues you felt were not appropriate to discuss during the interview, but that you are legitimately concerned about.
This might include questions around finance, accommodations (e.g., childcare, accessibility, etc.), immigration and many more.
I may not be able to help with all those aspects, but I can ask or point you towards appropriate resources.
We want to support our students not only as future researches, but also as individuals, so please, do not hesitate to bring up any concerns you have.
This is also a time for you to ask questions to help you decide which offer to accept (and we hope it will be UBC)!
We recruit bright students, most students will have multiple offers so you should feel free to discuss this openly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;acknowledgement&#34;&gt;Acknowledgement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.seltzer.com/margo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Margo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://aasthakm.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Aastha&lt;/a&gt; for their feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
